Welcome everyone to the showdown we've all been waiting for.
أهلًا بكم جميعًا إلى الدرس الذي ننتظره جميعًا.
In this corner is the new young upstart CSS grid.
في هذا الجانب نجد شبكة CSS الجديدة والناشئة.
In this corner, it's the old favorite that originally changed the game;
في هذا الجانب لدينا البرنامج المفضّل للكثيرين والذي غير طريقة العمل،
flexbox.
فليكس بوكس.
Okay, spoiler alert.
سنفشي لكم أمرًا.
Despite much speculation and drama on the web,
على الرغم من الأقوال الكثيرة والتوقعات على الويب،
the truth is that CSS grid does not replace flexbox.
فالحقيقة أن شبكة CSS لا تحلّ محل فليكس بوكس.
That is, each can achieve things that the other is not capable of and in fact,
فكلًا منهما ينجز مهام لا يمكن للآخر إنجازها، وفي الحقيقة فإن
a true master can use flexbox and CSS grid
المتمرس يستطيع استخدام شبكة CSS وفليكس بوكس معًا
together in harmony to create the ultimate web page layout.
بتوافق لإنشاء المخطط الأمثل لصفحات الويب.
In this section, we'll quickly cover some of
في هذا القسم سنتطرق إلى
the differences between CSS grid and flexbox,
الاختلافات بين شبكة CSS و فليكس بوكس،
highlight how they can work together,
ونسلط الضوء على كيفية عملهما معًا،
and then you'll take a deeper dive into the mechanics and syntax of CSS grid.
ثم نتناول بالتفصيل آليات وتراكيب جمل شبكة CSS.
At the highest level,
باختصار شديد،
CSS grid excels at creating layouts for a web page.
تتفوق شبكة CSS في إنشاء مخططات صفحات الويب،
While flexbox is a master of content flow for
أما فليكس بوكس فهو الأفضل لضبط تدفق المحتوى
each element that makes up the page layout. Let's learn some more.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
لكل عنصر من مكوّنات مخطط صفحة الويب. لنتعلم المزيد.